Kudakwashe Zinatsa

kmzinatsa@gmail.com 07871556851 https://www.linkedin.com/in/kudakwashe-zinatsa

SUMMARY

A highly self-driven, analytical, and process-oriented data analyst with 3 years' experience in data wrangling, data visualisation and interpreting data to drive business solutions. Seeking to apply my understanding of business operations and analytics tools as a data analyst.

EDUCATION

MSc Data Science, Nottingham Trent University, 2022 (Statistical data analysis, Applied AI, and data mining)

Advanced Certificate in Taxation and Customs, Zimbabwe Revenue Authority, 2015

Bachelor of Economics, Rhodes University, 2012 (Econometrics, Mathematical Statistics)

SKILL SETS, TRAINING & CERTIFICATIONS

Programming Languages Python, SQL, R, Excel VBA **Data Analysis and Visualisation tools** Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, PowerBI, Tableau, MS Excel **Soft Skills** Report Writing, Teamwork, Critical Thinking, Communication **Certifications** Google Analytics, Microsoft Azure Applied AI fundamentals

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst – Zimbabwe Revenue Authority

May 2019 - July 2021

- Collected, cleansed, transformed, and provided modelling and analyses of structured and unstructured data used for major policy initiatives. Outcomes: A 15% increase in revenue generated by increasing the tax base, resulting in \$10.2M collection.
- Created visually impactful dashboards in excel and powerBI for data reporting by using pivot tables, vlookup, xlookup and dax measures.
- Reported on performance of revenue by extracting, interpreting, and analysing data to identify key metrics and transformed raw data into meaningful, actionable information. Managed to reduce reporting time by 50% by formulating a template of a dashboard that could be re-used by others across multiple departments.

Tax Analyst – Zimbabwe Revenue Authority

May 2015 - April 2019

- Gathered, analysed, and interpreted data (identifying trends and providing commentary on potential causes) on tax revenue, attaining an increase in tax return compliance from 60% to 80% in 1 year. Recovered outstanding debt from a portfolio of 100 clients, reduced debt by 80% in 2 years.
- Liaised with taxpayers, attorneys, accountants, and company representatives regarding tax legislation issues and resolved queries within 3 working days. Attained the best query resolution rate in the section of 95% against a section average of 60%.
- Conducted audits for clients in the Mining and Agricultural sector, recovered 25% of the station target.

Tax Trainee – Zimbabwe Revenue Authority

May 2013 - April 2015

- Cleaned, transformed, and analysed tax data and information while assessing tax returns, using vlookup, pivot tables and SAP system. I achieved the highest assessment rate of 12 cases per week against section average of 9 cases per week.
- Collected taxes, monitored payment plans, and imposed deadlines on non-compliant taxpayers using Ms Excel
 to track portfolio performance.